Contact

p15rohanj@iima.ac.in

www.linkedin.com/in/jainrohanrj (LinkedIn) www.instagram.com/jainrohanrj/ (Blog)

Top Skills

Java

Python

С

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Elementary)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Passed CFA Level 1
Open Water Diver

Honors-Awards

Academic Excellence Award, IIT Kanpur

Gold Medal in Badminton, Sangharsh'16 (The Inter-IIM Sports Meet)

Silver Medal in Badminton, The Inter-IIT Sports Meet'13

Best Incoming Sportsperson, IIT Kanpur

Rohan Jain

Boston Consulting Group | IIM Ahmedabad | IIT Kanpur | Quora 105K+ followers

New Delhi

Summary

Rohan Jain is a Consultant at Boston Consulting Group (BCG). In the course of his 3 years at BCG so far, he has worked on a variety of projects in the Industrial Goods domain, across strategy and implementation. His experience ranges from topics related to overall operational transformation of large plants across the value chain and reduction in direct material costs using Design to Value principles to enabling the clients in their digital transformation journey.

He holds a Bachelors in Computer Science from Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, India and an MBA from Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad, India. He also holds a Masters in Management degree from EBS Business School, Germany.

In his free time, Rohan likes to maintain an active blog on Quora and a travel blog on Instagram. He has 105K+ followers on Quora with more than 28 Mn views in his content so far.

Quora: https://www.quora.com/profile/Rohan-Jain-16 Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/jainrohanrj/

Experience

Boston Consulting Group (BCG)

3 years 4 months

Consultant

June 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Senior Associate

May 2017 - May 2019 (2 years 1 month)

New Delhi Area, India

The Boston Consulting Group Summer Associate

April 2016 - June 2016 (3 months)

London Business School Research Assistant November 2014 - May 2015 (7 months) London, United Kingdom

EPFL (École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne) Research Intern

May 2014 - July 2014 (3 months)

Lausanne Area, Switzerland

Automation of CloudSuite Benchmarks - Parallel Systems Architecture Laboratory (PARSA)

- 1. Made the installation & execution user-friendly by automating the Data Serving Benchmark
- 2. The scripts were ported on both x86 and ARM running on different Linux distributions
- 3. Reduced running time of Data Serving Benchmark from hours to minutes

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) (2015 - 2017)

EBS Universität für Wirtschaft und Recht Master in Management, Major in Strategy and Consulting · (2016 - 2017)

Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science · (2011 - 2015)

Sanskriti School, New Delhi Science (2007 - 2011)